Guide to the Frank La Roche Photographs of Everett and Lowell, Washington 1891-1892
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Frank La Roche Photographs of Everett and Lowell, Washington
1891-1892
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
PC 73
La Roche, Frank, 1853-1934.
.5 Linear feet of shelf space 1 box 37 items
37 black and white photographs of Everett and Lowell, Washington, taken by photographer Frank La Roche in 1891 and 1892.
In October of 1891 photographer Frank La Roche (1853-1936), of Seattle, traveled north to Everett on commission for the Puget Sound Wire Nail and Steel Company, and began photographing the booming area. He returned to the region at least three more times in 1891-1892.
La Roche is best known for his photographs of the Klondike during the Alaskan gold rush in the 1890s.
37 black and white photographs of Everett and Lowell, Washington, taken during 1891 and 1892. The description in the item list below comes (excepting item numbers and the one date, which are taken from the photographs themselves) verbatim from captions pasted below the images.
The materials appear to be in their original order and format, with two 7"x10" black and white photographs pasted one to a side of each 9"x13" album page (one sheet is blank on one side).
This collection is open and available for research use.
This album was purchased by the Washington State College Library from Romaine Books (of Chicago) on March 10th, 1945, and placed in the regular stacks. It was transferred to Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC) in the late 1980s.
Another copy of this album appears to exist at the Everett Public Library, though it is unclear if it is identical or just contains several images in common.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Everett (Wash.) -- Pictorial works.; Lowell (Everett, Wash.) -- Pictorial works.; Washington (State) -- Pictorial works.
Washington (State); Photographs
- View of Lowell from opposite side of Snohomish River, showing whaleback "C.W. Wetmore" discharging at dock of Puget Sound Pulp and Paper Company. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Whaleback "C.W. Wetmore" at dock of Puget Sound Pulp and Paper Company. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Boarding house erected by the Puget Sound Pulp and Paper Company at Lowell. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Rear view of mill of Puget Sound Pulp and Paper Company. From the mill boarding house (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Snohomish, Skykomish, and Spokane R.R. bridge, across the Snohomish River at Lowell. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- View of paper mill at Lowell, showing whaleback, "C.W. Wetmore" at dock and construction of lime kiln. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cottages at Lowell on east side of Third Street, north and south of Eugene Street. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Cottages at Lowell on east side of Third Street, north of Eugene Street. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Railroad grade though Sines tract, looking north towards Everett. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Railroad grade though Sines tract, looking south towards Lowell. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- View down Chestnut Street, south from Hewitt Avenue. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- View up Chestnut Street north from Hewitt Avenue. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- View northwest up and Hewitt Avenue from corner of State Street. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- View down Hewitt Avenue towards Swalwell's wharf. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- View of Pacific Avenue looking west from Maple Street. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- View of Pine Street looking south from Pacific Avenue. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- View of Pacific Avenue looking east from Spruce Street. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Everett Hotel in course of construction. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- View of Pacific Avenue looking east from Oakes Street, and showing avenue partially graded. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bay View Hotel at Everett, showing also Everett Hotel in distance. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Rear view of Puget Sound Wire Nail and Steel Works, taken from railroad track. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Front view of Puget Sound Wire Nail and Steel Works, taken from end of dock. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- View of end of Nail Works dock with steamer "State of Washington" just landing. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- View of Everett townsite looking from the end of Nail Mill Wharf. No. 1061. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Swalwell's Landing on Snohomish River. No. 1060. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Paper Mill, north end. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Paper Mill, west side. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Paper Mill in course of construction, showing foundation of smoke stack. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Warehouse and main structure of Paper Mill, river side. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- E.D. Smith's Saw Mill at Lowell. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- View of Everett townsite and Seattle and Montana Railroad, looking north. No. 1058. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Looking north from Swalwell's Landing, showing sheer boom used for catching logs. No. 1055. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- View of Swalwell's Landing or "East Everett." No. 1056. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Looking south from "Bay View" Hotel on Puget Sound. No. 1059. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Paper Mill Boarding House. [group portrait] (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Nail Mill wharf, and warehouse in process of construction. No. 1057. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Showing town of Lowell, on the Snohomish River. No. 126. 1891. (Box 1, Folder 19)